Displayed here is the E.T.
这里显示的是
Rotten Tomatoes HTML data.
烂番茄网站《ET 外星人》的 HTML 数据
HTML files are text files that can be opened and
HTML 文件是可以在 Sublime 等文本编辑器中
inspected in text editors, like Sublime here.
打开和检查的文本文件
This means you can write your own code to parse or understand the text.
这也就是说 你可以编写自己的代码 来解析或理解文本
Sure, there's some confusing code at the top here,
当然 这里顶部有一些令人混淆的代码
but the actual text content of the web page,
但网页的实际文本内容
like the title and the critic and audience scores for example, that's pretty simple.
比如名称和影评人及观众评分 则是相当简单的
Like to get our audience score metrics,
比如 要获得观众评分指标
we could find all instances of the span tag in the text using something like Python
我们可以在文本中找到 span 标签的所有实例 其方法是
str.find function or a fancier tool called regular expressions,
利用像 Python str.find 函数或被称作正则表达式的更神奇的工具
to search for and extract patterns in text.
来搜索和提取文本中的模式
But, once again, people have come before us
但再说一次 在我们之前
and solved this problem in a spectacular fashion.
人们就开始以一种神奇的方式解决这个问题
Beautiful Soup is a HTML parser written in the Python programming language.
Beautiful Soup 是一个采用 Python 编程语言编写的 HTML 解析器
The name is derived from the tag soup term,
这个名称源自于 TagSoup 一词
in reference to the unstructured and almost unparsable HTML found on most web sites.
这与大多数网站上找到的几乎不可解析的非结构化 HTML 有关
Pause the video and take a second to read
如果愿意 你可以暂停视频 花上一秒钟的时间阅读
the library's rather convincing testimonials if you'd like.
库里相当具有说服力的证明
So, let's use this to extract the title of the movie from our E.T.
所以 我们利用它从《ET 外星人》 HTML 页面上提取电影名称
HTML page. We'll need this later when we're joining all of out gathered pieces of data.
我们稍后在合并所有已收集数据时会需要这个名称
So we'll go to the documentation.
接着 我们转至文档
The first thing you need to do is make the soup.
你需要做的第一件事是制作 soup
That means passing the path to your HTML file into a file handle,
也就是说 将引导至 HTML 文件的路径传递给文件句柄
then passing that file handle into the Beautiful Soup constructor, like so.
然后将文件句柄传递至 Beautiful Soup 构造函数 就像这样
That's after importing the Beautiful Soup library of course.
这是导入本课程 Beautiful Soup 库后的情景
And let's try this with our Rotten Tomatoes E.T.
我们对存储在 rt_html 文件夹中的
HTML which is stored in this rt_html folder.
烂番茄网站《ET 外星人》 HTML 试试这个方法。
So, there's our file path,
这是我们的文件路径
and we passed it into this file handle, file.
我们将它传递至文件句柄 文件
They have FP as file handle,
它们的文件句柄是 FP
but we've been using files so, let's stick with this.
但我们一直这么使用文件 所以我们坚持这么做
So, Beautiful Soup throws this warning which is
Beautiful Soup 给出这个警告
telling us that we didn't specify a specific parser.
它是在告诉我们 我们没有指定一个具体的解析器
Pause the video and take a second to read this if you'd like.
如果愿意 你可以暂停视频 花一点时间 阅读这段文字
By default, they actually picked the most popular parser for us which is called lxml,
默认情况下 它们会为我们挑选最受欢迎的解析器 叫做 lxml
and we'll actually pass this in here to get rid of this warning.
我们实际上进入这个解析器中 以摆脱警告
And we have our Soup, our Beautiful Soup.
我们有自己的 Soup 即我们的 Beautilful Soup
This looks exactly like an HTML document, but in actuality,
这看起来确实像一个 HTML 文件 但实际上
we can use methods in the Beautiful Soup library to
我们可以用 Beautiful Soup 库中的方法来
easily find and extract data from this HTML.
从这个 HTML 中轻松找到并提取数据
One of the most popular methods is the find method.
最受欢迎的方法之一就是 find 法
Let's find the title of our movie using this method.
我们来利用这种方法来找出我们的影片名称
Pause the video and take a second to read the first paragraph here.
暂停视频 花上一秒钟的时间来阅读第一段
It might not all make sense right away, but shortly it will.
你或许不会马上明白它的含义 但很快就会明白的
I promise you. Okay, so let's use find to get the title of our movie from our HTML.
我向你保证 好的 我们利用 find 从 HTML 中获得我们影片的名称
Think of Beautiful Soup's find method,
想想 Beautiful Soup 的 find 法
like the find feature in a text editor.
就像文本编辑器中的 find 功能一样
For example, i.e.
比如
Control+F or Command+F.
Control+F 或 Command+F
And if we search for our title tag,
如果我们搜索名称标签
we'll find that there's only one in this whole HTML document.
我们会发现整个 HTML 文档中只有一个
And within that tag is the movie title that we want.
我们想要的电影名称就在这个标签内
E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial, 1982.
ET 外星人 1982年
And here's how that looks in Beautiful Soup code, and there it is.
这就是它在 Beautiful Soup 代码中的模样 就这样
This title is actually the title of the web page and
这个名称实际上就是网页的名称
not the title of the movie which you can see up here.
而不是你能够在这里见到的电影的名称
To get the movie title only,
要想仅得到电影名称
we'll have to do some simple string slicing to remove that and bit there.
我们必须进行一些简单的字符串截取 以便除去它
The space - space rotten space tomatoes.
- rotten tomatoes
No worries, we can do that. Okay. So, to access the contents of this tag, i.e.
不用担心 我们能够做到 好的 比如说 要想访问这个标签的内容
whatever's within these opening and closing tags,
不论这些开放标签和闭合标签之中有什么
we can use dot contents.
我们都可以使用 .contents
Dot contents returns a list of the tags children and there's the list.
contents 返回一个标签 children 的名单 名单就在这里
Because there's only one thing within this tag,
由于这个标签之中只有一个对象
the list is one item long and we can never access it using the index 0.
所以 名单中也只有一个项目 我们不能使用索引 0 来访问
And here's what string slicing looks like to just get
这就是仅仅为了获得电影名称和电影发行年份
the movie title and the year the movie was released.
而所做的字符串截取的情形
This string splicing just grabbed everything from the first character in
字符串截取仅抓取从字符串中第一个字符
our string to the 18th last character.
到倒数第 18 个字符的内容
The length of the string space dash space rotten space tomatoes, being 18 characters.
字符串 - rotten tomatoes的长度 为 18 个字符
So, this xa0 thing is unicode for non-breaking space.
所以 xa0 是不间断空格的 Unicode编码
Unicode stuff is something we'll cover shortly.
我们稍后会讲到 Unicaode 编码
So, don't worry if it doesn't make sense to you right now.
所以 如果你现在还不明白 请不要担心
The reason why I'm bringing this up is because
我之所以提出这一点 是因为
the original Top 100 TSV file actually doesn't have a non-breaking space here,
原始的 Top 100 TSV 文件实际上在电影末尾和电影发行年份
in between the end of the movie and the year of the movie release,
之间并没有不间断空格
it just has a regular space.
它只有一个正常空格
So we'll have to standardize these when cleaning,
所以 我们在清理时必须进行标准化
so we can later join data frames on the title column.
这样 我们以后就能在名称列合并 DataFrame
We actually won't do any cleaning in this lesson,
在这堂课中 我们实际上并未进行任何清理
so just keep this in mind for now.
暂时只要记住它就行